<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Turing Scholars Honors Program</title>
    <link href="https://tssa.painful.systems/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://tssa.painful.systems" />
    <updated>2022-04-06T14:32:50-05:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>TSSA Board</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://tssa.painful.systems</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Honors Faculty</title>
        <author>
            <name>TSSA Board</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://tssa.painful.systems/faculty.html"/>
        <id>https://tssa.painful.systems/faculty.html</id>
            <category term="About Turing"/>

        <updated>2022-03-22T14:30:08-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Classes are led by world-renowned research faculty and leading industry experts who provide individual guidance and mentorship to students. Calvin Lin is a University Distinguished Teaching Professor with research interests in computer architecture, compilers, and security. In addition to his technical research, he has led&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Classes are led by world-renowned research faculty and leading industry experts who provide individual guidance and mentorship to students.</p>
<h3><a href="https://www.cs.utexas.edu/~lin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span class="link-annotation-unknown-block-id-1801608881">Calvin Lin</span></a></h3>
<p>Calvin Lin is a University Distinguished Teaching Professor with research interests in computer architecture, compilers, and security. In addition to his technical research, he has led UT's NSF-funded effort to improve high school CS curricula. He is also the Director of the Turing Scholars Honors Program and the longtime coach of UT's Men's Ultimate Frisbee team. He has been awarded the Jean Holloway Award for Excellence in Teaching, one of the university's highest honors for teaching excellence. Dr. Lin received his BS from Princeton and his PhD from the University of Washington.</p>
<p>Honors courses: C S 314H Data Structures and Algorithms, C S 178H Intro to Research</p>
<h3><a href="https://www.cs.utexas.edu/~isil/"><span class="link-annotation-unknown-block-id-12824943">I</span>ş<span class="link-annotation-unknown-block-id-12824943">il Dillig</span></a></h3>
<p>Işil Dillig is an associate professor of computer science. Her main research areas are programming languages and formal methods (program verification and synthesis), but her research also touches on security, databases, and artificial intelligence. Dr. Dillig obtained all her degrees (BS, MS, PhD) from Stanford University, and she is also a Sloan Fellow as as well as an NSF CAREER award recipient. Her research has been recognized by numerous awards, including best paper awards at PLDI, OOPSLA, and ETAPS, and a CACM research highlight. Dr. Dillig has served as co-chair of CAV, the premier conference in Formal Methods, and she has served on program committees of most major programming languages and formal methods conferences.</p>
<p>Honors courses: C S 311H Discrete Math</p>
<h3><a href="https://www.cs.utexas.edu/people/faculty-researchers/ahmed-gheith">Ahmed Gheith</a></h3>
<p>Ahmed Gheith is an adjunct assistant professor of computer science. His interests are in research and advanced development of computer systems with an emphasis on computer architecture, operating systems, language run-times, and system middleware. He has a PhD from Georgia Tech, an MA from The Ohio State University, and a BSc from Alexandria University in Egypt.</p>
<p>Honors courses: C S 429H Computer Organization and Architecture, C S 439H Principles of Computer Systems</p>
<h3><a href="https://www.cs.utexas.edu/~ecprice/">Eric Price</a></h3>
<p>Eric Price is an assistant professor of computer science. His undergraduate and graduate education was at MIT, where Piotr Indyk was his advisor. After graduating in 2013, he was a postdoc at the Simons Institute in Berkeley and at the IBM Almaden Research Center before arriving at UT in Fall 2014.</p>
<p>Honors courses: C S 331H Algorithms and Complexity</p>
<h3><a href="http://www.cs.utexas.edu/~vlr/" class="notion-link-token notion-enable-hover" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-token-index="0" data-reactroot=""><span class="link-annotation-unknown-block-id--66159741">Vijaya Ramachandran</span></a></h3>
<p>Vijaya Ramachandran is the William Blakemore II Regents Professor in Computer Science. Her research interests are in theoretical computer science in the areas of algorithm design and analysis, data structures, graph theory and algorithms, and parallel computation. Dr. Ramachandran received her Ph.D. from Princeton University.</p>
<p>Honors courses: C S 331H Algorithms and Complexity</p>
<h3><a href="http://www.cs.utexas.edu/~rossbach/">Chris Rossbach</a></h3>
<p>Chris Rossbach is an assistant professor of computer science, a senior affiliated researcher at VMware Research Group, and a former Member of Microsoft Research Silicon Valley. His research is in operating systems, virtualization, accelerators, and emerging architecture. He received his PhD from UT Austin and his BS from Stanford.</p>
<p>Honors courses: C S 378H Concurrency</p>
<h3><a href="https://www.scottaaronson.com/">Scott Aaronson</a></h3>
<p>Scott Aaronson is the David J. Bruton Centennial Professor of Computer Science at the University of Texas at Austin and director of its Quantum Information Center. Prior to joining UT, he taught for nine years at MIT. His research interests center around the capabilities and limits of quantum computers, and computational complexity theory more generally.</p>
<p>Honors courses: C S 358H Introduction to Quantum Information Science</p>
<h3><a href="https://www.cs.utexas.edu/~hovav/">Hovav Shacham</a></h3>
<p>Hovav Shacham joined the University of Texas at Austin in 2018. His research interests are in applied cryptography, systems security, privacy-enhancing technologies, and technology policy. Shacham was a student at Stanford and a postdoctoral fellow at the Weizmann Institute. From 2007 to 2018, he was on the faculty at the University of California, San Diego. He received the 2017 ACM CCS Test-of-Time Award for his 2007 paper that introduced return-oriented programming. Shacham took part in California’s 2007 “Top-to-Bottom” voting systems review and served on the advisory committee for California’s 2011-13 post-election risk-limiting audit pilot program. His work has been cited by the Federal Trade Commission, the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, and the RAND Corporation.</p>
<p>Honors courses: C S 378H Network Security</p>
<h3><a href="http://www.cs.utexas.edu/users/grauman/">Kristen Grauman</a></h3>
<p>Kristen Grauman is a Full Professor in the Department of Computer Science where she leads the UT Computer Vision Group. Her research is in computer vision and machine learning. She is a Fellow of AAAI, an Alfred P. Sloan Research Fellow, and a recipient of the Presidential Early Career Award for Scientists and Engineers, the 2013 Computers and Thought Award, and several best paper awards. Prof. Grauman serves as Associate Editor-in-Chief for the IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence. She was elected to the Academy of Distinguished Teachers in 2017, and received her B.A. from Boston College and her Ph.D. from MIT.</p>
<p>Honors courses: C S 378H Machine Learning and Vision</p>
<h3><a href="https://www.cs.utexas.edu/~pstone/">Peter Stone</a></h3>
<p>Peter Stone is the David Bruton Jr. Centennial Professor of Computer Science and founded and directs the Learning Agents Research Group (LARG) within the Artificial Intelligence Laboratory. He is also the Executive Director of Sony AI America and an Alfred P. Sloan Research Fellow, Guggenheim Fellow, AAAI Fellow, and Fulbright Scholar. His main area of research is AI, focusing on machine learning, multiagent systems, and robotics.</p>
<p>Honors courses: C S 343H Artificial Intelligence</p>
<h3><a href="https://www.cs.utexas.edu/~sniekum/index.php">Scott Niekum</a></h3>
<p>Scott Niekum is an assistant professor and the director of the Personal Autonomous Robotics Lab (PeARL) in the Department of Computer Science. He is also the recipient of the NSF CAREER Award, the AFOSR Young Investigator Award, and the UT Austin CNS Teaching Excellence Award. His research focuses on machine learning and robotics, including topics such as imitation learning, reinforcement learning, probabilistic safety, manipulation, and human-robot interaction.</p>
<p>Honors courses: C S 343H Artificial Intelligence</p>
<h3><a href="https://www.cs.utexas.edu/people/faculty-researchers/adam-klivans">Adam Klivans</a></h3>
<p>Adam Klivans is a full professor in the Department of Computer Science. His research interests lie in machine learning and theoretical computer science, in particular, Learning Theory, Computational Complexity, Pseudorandomness, Limit Theorems, and Gaussian Space. He also serves on the editorial board for the Theory of Computing and Machine Learning Journal. Adam Klivans will also be directing the newly established campus wide <a href="https://ml.utexas.edu/">Machine Learning Laboratory</a>, the winner of the NSF AI institute competition.</p>
<p>Honors courses: C S 378H Introduction to Data Mining/Machine Learning Honors</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Honors Core</title>
        <author>
            <name>TSSA Board</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://tssa.painful.systems/honors-core.html"/>
        <id>https://tssa.painful.systems/honors-core.html</id>
            <category term="About Turing"/>

        <updated>2022-04-06T14:32:50-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    The honors core consists of six introductory classes that Turing students take during their freshmen and sophomore years. Turing students then choose additional honors CS electives, as well as department-wide CS electives. You can find a typical four-year honors degree plan on the UTCS degree&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>The honors core consists of six introductory classes that Turing students take during their freshmen and sophomore years. Turing students then choose additional honors CS electives, as well as department-wide CS electives. </p>
<p>You can find a typical four-year honors degree plan on the <a href="https://www.cs.utexas.edu/undergraduate-program/academics/curriculum/degree-plans" class="notion-link-token notion-enable-hover" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-token-index="1" data-reactroot=""><span class="link-annotation-unknown-block-id-1797084410">UTCS degree plans page</span></a>.</p>
<h3><span class="notion-enable-hover" data-token-index="0" data-reactroot="">C S 314H: Data Structures</span></h3>
<p>Students are introduced to advanced data structures and trained in software engineering techniques such as test methodology and agile workflow. Students complete a set of diverse and challenging programming projects, such as building a basic search engine or building a basic genetic algorithm to play Tetris.</p>
<p>Topics include: Java, object oriented programming, programming techniques, debugging, algorithm analysis, stacks, queues, linked lists, recursion, sorting, trees, hash tables, balanced trees, priority queue, graphs</p>
<h3><span class="notion-enable-hover" data-token-index="0" data-reactroot="">C S 311H: Discrete Mathematics for Computer Science</span></h3>
<p>Students are taught how to think mathematically and write proofs. Students are exposed to the fundamentals of Computer Science theory, such as graph theory, combinatorics, and mathematical induction. They learn to express problems mathematically and formally reason about computer science phenomena. Students are also exposed to automated theorem provers, and modern tools programmers use to reason about their program’s correctness formally.</p>
<p>Topic Include: Proofs, Set Theory, Number Theory, Graph Theory, Combinatorics, Induction, Contradiction, Recursion, Automated Theorem Provers, Master Theorem</p>
<h3><span class="notion-enable-hover" data-token-index="0" data-reactroot="">C S 429H: Computer Organization and Architecture</span></h3>
<p>Students learn about how a computer works - from transistors and logic gates to the compiler level - and how hardware and software work together. This is an intensive project based class in which, from scratch, students write a pipelined architecture in Verilog (a popular Hardware Design Language). Students are also taught C in this class as only prior knowledge of Java is assumed. Additionally students are required to blackbox test all projects and are responsible for writing clear efficient code to this end. Papers corresponding to particular projects are read and discussed. The class includes a capstone small group project where students are expected to build on a class project in novel ways.</p>
<p>Topics Include: Transistors, Logic Gates, Logic Diagrams, Processor Diagrams, Compilation, Thread Contexts, ISA Construction, Pipelining, Super Scalar, Cache Coherency, Atomics</p>
<h3><span class="notion-enable-hover" data-token-index="0" data-reactroot="">C S 439H: Principles of Computer Systems</span></h3>
<p>Students learn the building blocks of modern operating systems. They build a monolithic kernel from scratch in individual projects. Additionally they read relevant systems papers to enhance their understanding of why certain systems were developed the way they were.</p>
<p>Students learn to black and white box test each component of an operating system. They are assessed on the quality of their code as well as the novelty of their approach.</p>
<p>The class includes a final capstone class project, where the entire class works to build a fully functional operating system with graphics, sound, terminal interfaces etc. Students define their own standards and practices and rely on the faculty only when they encounter significant difficulty with a particular operating system concept. Generally this class is taught in C++ with a bit of Rust sprinkled in.</p>
<p>Topics Include: Threads, Processes, Synchronization Primitives, File Systems, Virtual Memory, Page Caches, Heap, Syscalls, fork and exec, Elf-Loading</p>
<h3>C S 331H: Algorithms and Complexity</h3>
<p>Students learn fundamental algorithms and complexity theory. This course is heavily proof-based and focuses on theory. Topics covered include dynamic programming, graph theory, and complexity theory. This class includes both a mathematical discovery of algorithms and the application of such techniques to code.</p>
<p>Topics Include: Dynamic Programming, Interval Scheduling, The Knapsack Problems, Path Finding, Max Flow, Algorithm Analysis, Complexity Analysis, Probabilistic Algorithms</p>
<h3>C S 178H: Introduction to CS Research</h3>
<p>This course helps students make the transition from classroom learning to the type of faculty-advised independent learning that is necessary to complete an honors thesis. This class gives students concrete advice about how to start researching with professors at UT, and offers practice and hands-on experience with the mechanics of research at the undergraduate and graduate level.</p>
<p>Topics Include: The research Process, Academic Reading and Writing, Graduate School, graduate school applications, the trajectory of an academic career, the role of research in industry, road to the Turing thesis.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Admissions</title>
        <author>
            <name>TSSA Board</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://tssa.painful.systems/admissions.html"/>
        <id>https://tssa.painful.systems/admissions.html</id>
            <category term="About Turing"/>

        <updated>2022-02-17T15:53:46-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Visit Us Note: Due to COVID-19, our tour policy has changed. Please see the department website for more information. The UT Department of Computer Science department offers informational tours for its undergraduate computer science programs throughout the year, including an honors tour focusing on the&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h2><span class="notion-enable-hover" data-token-index="0" data-reactroot="">Visit Us</span></h2>
<p class="msg msg--info">Note: Due to COVID-19, our tour policy has changed. Please see the <a href="https://www.cs.utexas.edu/undergraduate-program/admissions/schedule-visit" class="notion-link-token notion-enable-hover" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-token-index="1" data-reactroot=""><span class="link-annotation-unknown-block-id-1621193210">department website</span></a> for more information.</p>
<p>The UT Department of Computer Science department offers informational tours for its undergraduate computer science programs throughout the year, including an honors tour focusing on the Turing Scholars program as well as Texas CSB (CS + Business honors).</p>
<p>During your time on campus, you will have the opportunity to tour our state-of-the-art computer science facilities, attend a class, meet with an academic advisor, chat with a current student, and, if you sign up for the honors tour, visit with Professor Calvin Lin, the Director of the Turing Scholars program.</p>
<p>Students interested in honors visits are encouraged to come in the Fall when they can attend a first-year honors course. Spring visitors will need to visit a traditional, rather than an honors, class. Note that during the Spring semester, priority is given to admitted students.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.cs.utexas.edu/undergraduate-program/admissions/schedule-visit" class="notion-link-token notion-enable-hover" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-token-index="0" data-reactroot=""><span class="link-annotation-unknown-block-id-1621193210">Please visit the CS website for more information and to schedule a tour.</span></a></p>
<hr>
<h2><span class="notion-enable-hover" data-token-index="0" data-reactroot="">How do I apply?</span></h2>
<p>High school seniors can apply to the Turing Scholars Honors Program alongside the standard UT Austin application, as long as they select Computer Science as either their first or second choice major. The honors application process includes short-answer questions and an expanded resume and can be completed within the ApplyTexas/Coalition portal or on UT Austin's MyStatus page after submission of the UT application.</p>
<p>The admissions comittee is looking for highly motivated students with strong math and science backgrounds. A demonstrated interest in computer science through classes or personal projects is a plus, and evidence of leadership as exhibited by significant extracurricular involvement is also helpful.</p>
<p>For more information about applying to freshman honors, visit the <a href="https://admissions.utexas.edu/apply/freshman-honors" class="notion-link-token notion-enable-hover" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-token-index="1" data-reactroot=""><span class="link-annotation-unknown-block-id--882406885">Texas Admissions page</span></a>.</p>
<h2><span class="notion-enable-hover" data-token-index="0" data-reactroot="">For Current UT Students</span></h2>
<p>If you are interested in joining the Turing Scholars Honors Program and have excelled in your current CS and math courses at UT, please consider the following options:</p>
<h6>Join the Turing Scholars program</h6>
<p>Current CS majors can apply for admission to the Turing Scholars Honors Program at the end of each semester by submitting an <a href="https://utexas.qualtrics.com/SE/?SID=SV_6roHP2CPrgWJtmR" class="notion-link-token notion-enable-hover" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-token-index="1" data-reactroot=""><span class="link-annotation-unknown-block-id--1558725779">online application</span></a> and then emailing a resume to the address on the online application.</p>
<h6>Enroll in individual honors courses</h6>
<p>Our CS honors courses typically have a limited number of spaces available for non-Turing Scholars. Enrollment in honors courses is particularly useful for students who wish to transfer into the Turing Scholars Program, since they give the admissions committee an excellent way to evaluate your potential.</p>
<p>To apply, you should submit a separate <a href="https://www.cs.utexas.edu/undergraduate/academics/advising/forms" class="notion-link-token notion-enable-hover" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-token-index="1" data-reactroot=""><span class="link-annotation-unknown-block-id-905944319">request</span></a> for each CS honors course that you wish to take, since the decisions are made by the individual faculty members who teach the course. In some cases, faculty may ask you to also make an appointment for an interview.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Student Life</title>
        <author>
            <name>TSSA Board</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://tssa.painful.systems/student-lif.html"/>
        <id>https://tssa.painful.systems/student-lif.html</id>
            <category term="About Turing"/>

        <updated>2022-03-22T13:44:56-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://tssa.painful.systems/media/posts/3/DSC_0104.JPG" alt="" />
                    Social Spaces There are many great ways to spend time with our community outside of social events. Several spaces are frequented by Turing scholars: The Turing Scholars Student Association has an office on the third floor of the Gates Dell Complex. You'll always be able&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://tssa.painful.systems/media/posts/3/DSC_0104.JPG" alt="" />
                <div class="post__toc">
<h3> </h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1fs4n00ml9d">Turing Scholars Student Association</a></li>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1fs4n00ml9e">Turing Intramural Sports</a></li>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1fs4n00ml9f">Social Spaces</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1fs4n00ml9g">TSSA Office</a></li>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1fs4n00ml9h">Honors Dorms</a></li>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1fs4n00ml9i">Bill and Melinda Gates Computer Science Complex and Dell Hall</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1fs4n00ml9j">Women in Turing</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1fs4n00ml9k">Women in Turing Scholars (WiTS) and Women's Coffee</a></li>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1fs4n00ml9l">Women in Computer Science (WiCS)</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1fs4n00ml9m">Big/Little Endian Program</a></li>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1fs4n00ml9n">Corporate Sponsors 2021-2022</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1fs4n00ml9d">Turing Scholars Student Association</h2>
<p>The Turing Scholars Student Association (TSSA) is a student organization that regularly hosts free social events for Turing Scholars, including food! Examples of recent events include bowling, a catered Shaved Ice truck social, kickball, a nerf gun battle, super smash bros. tournaments, PowerPoint karaoke, a trick-or-treating research social with professors, and much more. The TSSA is able to hold these events thanks to generous sponsors who support the organization and hold private recruiting events for Turing Scholars.</p>
<p>At the end of each semester, the TSSA hosts a banquet celebrating our graduating seniors and the accomplishments of our Turing Scholars throughout the semester. Faculty are also invited, and trivia games ensue.</p>
<div class="gallery-wrapper gallery-wrapper--wide"><div class="gallery"  data-is-empty="false" data-columns="3">
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://tssa.painful.systems/media/posts/3/gallery/DSC_0041.JPG" data-size="6000x4000"><img loading="lazy" src="https://tssa.painful.systems/media/posts/3/gallery/DSC_0041-thumbnail.JPG" alt="" width="720" height="480"></a>
<figcaption>Turing Scholars play Kahoot! at the fall banquet.</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://tssa.painful.systems/media/posts/3/gallery/IMG_2635.jpeg" data-size="4032x3024"><img loading="lazy" src="https://tssa.painful.systems/media/posts/3/gallery/IMG_2635-thumbnail.jpeg" alt="" width="720" height="540"></a>
<figcaption>Students enjoy shaved ice at a TSSA social event.</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://tssa.painful.systems/media/posts/3/gallery/IMG_2788.png" data-size="4032x3024"><img loading="lazy" src="https://tssa.painful.systems/media/posts/3/gallery/IMG_2788-thumbnail.png" alt="" width="720" height="540"></a>
<figcaption>Dr. Chris Rossbach plays guitar at a research event organized by the TSSA.</figcaption>
</figure>
</div></div>
<hr>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1fs4n00ml9e">Turing Intramural Sports</h2>
<p>Turing Scholars passionate about athletics often come together and form Turing-wide intramural (IM) sports teams every semester. Team practices are a great way to get to know other Turing Scholars while staying active.</p>
<p>The most popular Turing teams are The Floppy Disks (ultimate frisbee) and Foo Barcelona (soccer). Turing Scholars have also assembled IM teams for basketball, volleyball, racquetball, flag football, and dodgeball. The TSSA covers all team registration fees at no cost to students.</p>
<div class="gallery-wrapper"><div class="gallery"  data-is-empty="false" data-columns="2">
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://tssa.painful.systems/media/posts/3/gallery/73190488_2348627061932577_3732530290522849280_n_1.jpg" data-size="3024x4032"><img loading="lazy" src="https://tssa.painful.systems/media/posts/3/gallery/73190488_2348627061932577_3732530290522849280_n_1-thumbnail.jpg" alt="" width="720" height="960"></a>
<figcaption>The Floppy Disks (19-20)</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://tssa.painful.systems/media/posts/3/gallery/IMG_7729.jpg" data-size="4032x3024"><img loading="lazy" src="https://tssa.painful.systems/media/posts/3/gallery/IMG_7729-thumbnail.jpg" alt="" width="720" height="540"></a>
<figcaption>Foo Barcelona (19-20)</figcaption>
</figure>
</div></div>
<hr>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1fs4n00ml9f">Social Spaces</h2>
<p>There are many great ways to spend time with our community outside of social events. Several spaces are frequented by Turing scholars:</p>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1fs4n00ml9g">TSSA Office</h3>
<p>The Turing Scholars Student Association has an office on the third floor of the Gates Dell Complex. You'll always be able to find Turing Scholars working, socializing, and hanging out in the TSSA office from 12-5pm on weekdays.</p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://tssa.painful.systems/media/posts/3/118398541_730446681143665_2737914797078525540_n.jpg" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="https://tssa.painful.systems/media/posts/3/responsive/118398541_730446681143665_2737914797078525540_n-xs.jpg 300w ,https://tssa.painful.systems/media/posts/3/responsive/118398541_730446681143665_2737914797078525540_n-sm.jpg 480w ,https://tssa.painful.systems/media/posts/3/responsive/118398541_730446681143665_2737914797078525540_n-md.jpg 768w ,https://tssa.painful.systems/media/posts/3/responsive/118398541_730446681143665_2737914797078525540_n-lg.jpg 1024w ,https://tssa.painful.systems/media/posts/3/responsive/118398541_730446681143665_2737914797078525540_n-xl.jpg 1360w ,https://tssa.painful.systems/media/posts/3/responsive/118398541_730446681143665_2737914797078525540_n-2xl.jpg 1600w"  alt="" width="2000" height="972"></figure>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1fs4n00ml9h">Honors Dorms</h3>
<p>Many first year Turing students choose to study together in the lobbies of the dorms that make up the Honors Quad. Students explain complex ideas to each other, study for exams together, and support each other completing common assignments.</p>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1fs4n00ml9i"><strong>Bill and Melinda Gates Computer Science Complex and Dell Hall</strong></h3>
<p>In addition to the above spaces, the Gates Dell Complex (GDC) provides ample space for Turing Scholars to socialize and work together. Home to the Department of Computer Science, there are 2 computer labs (on the 1st and 3rd floor) where Computer Science students can work as well as numerous common areas and rooms to study in.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1fs4n00ml9j">Women in Turing</h2>
<p>Women comprise approximately 25% of each Turing class on average. While this percentage is significantly higher than the national average, director Dr. Calvin Lin says "it’s something we want to further improve upon," seeking to focus on high school outreach and dig deeper into the root causes of the imbalance. In the short term, women in the Turing Scholars Honors Program have a host of opportunities and ways to seek community:</p>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1fs4n00ml9k">Women in Turing Scholars (WiTS) and Women's Coffee</h3>
<p>There is a strong sense of community among Women in Turing Scholars (WiTS). From group chats to study groups to boba tea runs, WiTS maintains an active and welcoming community and support system. TSSA also hosts an annual catered Women's Coffee, inviting female students and faculty to engage in a safe space.</p>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1fs4n00ml9l">Women in Computer Science (WiCS)</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.cs.utexas.edu/~wics/" class="notion-link-token notion-enable-hover" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-token-index="0" data-reactroot=""><span class="link-annotation-unknown-block-id-25450778">WiCS</span></a> is a student organization within the UTCS department. Their mission is to encourage and support women in computing through outreach, professional development, academic initiatives, and social events. Many women in Turing regularly participate in WiCS events, engaging with women in CS both in and outside of the Turing program.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1fs4n00ml9m">Big/Little Program</h2>
<p>The Big/Little Program is a program where incoming students are paired with an upperclass Turing Scholar. These pairs are made based on information collected from both the upperclass student and the first-year student to make sure that students are paired with someone who can offer advice and provide information.</p>
<p>Bigs help Littles adjust to the college environment and help them navigate the corporate, research, and social sides of computer science. Bigs make sure that new students have the information they need to thrive, and they provide access to any community resources that may be useful in this transitory period. We find that these relationships last well beyond this first year and help foster growth and interaction in the overall Turing community.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://resilient-sing-a1b.notion.site/image/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fsecure.notion-static.com%2Fceaff314-4302-4735-b675-5eace44b3525%2FUntitled.png?table=block&amp;id=98d83fa3-d197-4bf0-a689-e5553cb78755&amp;spaceId=0abb7c3e-d22c-4aec-9dbc-25db245630b8&amp;width=1060&amp;userId=&amp;cache=v2" data-is-external-image="true" ></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1fs4n00ml9n">Corporate Sponsors (2021-2022)</h2>
<p>The high demand for Turing Scholars spurs more companies every year to sponsor the TSSA. These companies hold private recruiting events for Turing Scholars which enable prospective interns and full-time employees to network with recruiters and drop off resumes. Sponsorship proceeds are used to hold social activities for Turing Scholars year-round, with leftover money put into an endowment for student scholarships. (Did we mention, the companies always bring food?)</p>
<p>The TSSA thanks the following companies for their support during the 2021-2022 school year:</p>
<p><strong><span class="notion-enable-hover" data-token-index="0" data-reactroot="">Turing Tier:</span></strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://8vc.com/" class="notion-link-token notion-enable-hover" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-token-index="0" data-reactroot=""><span class="link-annotation-unknown-block-id-2060684966">8VC</span></a></li>
<li><a href="http://apple.com/" class="notion-link-token notion-enable-hover" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-token-index="0" data-reactroot=""><span class="link-annotation-unknown-block-id-2102737691">Apple</span></a></li>
<li><a href="http://citadel.com/" class="notion-link-token notion-enable-hover" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-token-index="0" data-reactroot=""><span class="link-annotation-unknown-block-id--59475175">Citadel | Citadel Securities</span></a></li>
<li><a href="http://janestreet.com/" class="notion-link-token notion-enable-hover" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-token-index="0" data-reactroot=""><span class="link-annotation-unknown-block-id-637872982">Jane Street</span></a></li>
<li><a href="https://roblox.com/" class="notion-link-token notion-enable-hover" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-token-index="0" data-reactroot=""><span class="link-annotation-unknown-block-id-437173778">Roblox</span></a></li>
<li><a href="https://snowflake.com/" class="notion-link-token notion-enable-hover" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-token-index="0" data-reactroot=""><span class="link-annotation-unknown-block-id--787118474">Snowflake</span></a></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Djikstra Tier:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://bloomberg.com/" class="notion-link-token notion-enable-hover" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-token-index="0" data-reactroot=""><span class="link-annotation-unknown-block-id-661492959">Bloomberg</span></a></li>
<li><a href="https://cloudflare.com/" class="notion-link-token notion-enable-hover" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-token-index="0" data-reactroot=""><span class="link-annotation-unknown-block-id-1234052443">Cloudflare</span></a></li>
<li><a href="http://convoy.com/" class="notion-link-token notion-enable-hover" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-token-index="0" data-reactroot=""><span class="link-annotation-unknown-block-id--671766717">Convoy</span></a></li>
<li><a href="https://indeed.com/" class="notion-link-token notion-enable-hover" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-token-index="0" data-reactroot=""><span class="link-annotation-unknown-block-id-981582759">Indeed</span></a></li>
</ul>
<p>If you're interested in learning more about sponsorship opportunities with the TSSA, please email <span class="notion-enable-hover" data-token-index="1" data-reactroot="">tssacorporate at cs.utexas.edu</span>.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Academics</title>
        <author>
            <name>TSSA Board</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://tssa.painful.systems/academics.html"/>
        <id>https://tssa.painful.systems/academics.html</id>
            <category term="About Turing"/>

        <updated>2022-03-22T14:29:30-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://tssa.painful.systems/media/posts/2/IMG_4014.jpeg" alt="" />
                    The Turing Scholars degree plan largely mimics our traditional CS degree plan but includes 10 honors courses that challenge our students in different ways. Highlights of our honors curriculum include: To see a typical four-year plan, check out the Honors section in the UTCS degree&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://tssa.painful.systems/media/posts/2/IMG_4014.jpeg" alt="" />
                <p>The Turing Scholars degree plan largely mimics our traditional CS degree plan but includes 10 honors courses that challenge our students in different ways. Highlights of our honors curriculum include:</p>
<ul>
<li>An intensive, accelerated set of classes in freshman year, taken with a cohort of honors students</li>
<li>Small classes (30-60 students), which offer more room for students to engage with professors</li>
<li>Reserved seating in upper-division honors electives, from quantum information to network security</li>
<li>Two undergraduate research courses that culminate in an undergraduate honors thesis</li>
</ul>
<p>To see a typical four-year plan, check out the Honors section in the <span class="link-annotation-unknown-block-id-1797084410"><a href="https://www.cs.utexas.edu/undergraduate-program/academics/curriculum/degree-plans" class="notion-link-token notion-enable-hover" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-token-index="1" data-reactroot="">UTCS degree plans page</a>.</span></p>
<h3><a href="file:///Users/meyer/Documents/Publii/sites/turing-scholars-honors-program/preview/why-turing.html">» </a><a href="https://tssa.painful.systems/honors-core.html">Honors core</a></h3>
<p>The honors core consists of six introductory classes that Turing students take during their freshmen and sophomore years. Turing students then choose additional honors CS electives, as well as department-wide CS electives.</p>
<p>Students take honors classes covering data structures, discrete mathematics, computer architecture, operating systems, and algorithms, typically in the first two years.</p>
<p>Over the course of their core, students build a web crawler and search engine, a basic compiler, a pipelined processor in Verilog, an operating system kernel with preemptive multithreading and virtual memory, a driver for the real ext2 file system, and much more.</p>
<h3><a href="https://tssa.painful.systems/faculty.html">» World-class faculty</a></h3>
<p>Honors classes are taught by faculty who work at the cutting-edge of computer science and who have demonstrated excellence in teaching.</p>
<h3>Research</h3>
<p>Turing Scholars are encouraged to begin undergraduate research as early as possible, and we have created many programs and events to facilitate such research.</p>
<p>Turing Scholars complete an honors thesis as part of their degree through a research project with a member of our faculty. During the second semester of their freshmen year, students take a course about conducting research in computer science. This course introduces the department's research faculty and their research interests.</p>
<h4><span class="notion-enable-hover" data-token-index="0" data-reactroot="">Directed Reading Program (DiRP)</span></h4>
<p>Every semester, the Turing Scholars Student Association organizes a program called the CS Directed Reading Program (DiRP). Upperclassmen and graduate students who have done research in a particular subfield apply and are selected to serve as mentors for students interested in it. Reading Groups will meet each week to discuss papers and other sources to further students’ understanding of the group’s topic. Group mentors also serve as advisors when applying to certain labs. This allows Turing Scholars, as well as the overall UTCS community, to get more comfortable with the process of research.</p>
<h4>Faculty Research Talks</h4>
<p>Every week, a faculty member is invited to present their research to Turing Scholars. These allow students to interact with faculty outside of the classroom, learn more about the various specializations in CS, and find an interesting problem for their undergraduate thesis.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Why Turing?</title>
        <author>
            <name>TSSA Board</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://tssa.painful.systems/why-turing.html"/>
        <id>https://tssa.painful.systems/why-turing.html</id>
            <category term="About Turing"/>

        <updated>2022-03-22T13:48:32-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://tssa.painful.systems/media/posts/1/IMG_2634.jpeg" alt="" />
                    The Turing Scholars Program is unique. By serving a small number of truly outstanding students—we typically matriculate about 50 first-year Turing Scholars each fall—we are able to provide an outstanding learning experience that combines the resources of a large university with the benefits of a&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://tssa.painful.systems/media/posts/1/IMG_2634.jpeg" alt="" />
                <p><strong>The Turing Scholars Program is unique.</strong> By serving a small number of truly outstanding students—we typically matriculate about 50 first-year Turing Scholars each fall—we are able to provide an outstanding learning experience that combines the resources of a large university with the benefits of a small community.</p>
<p>In particular, our goal is to recruit the best students from around the country, to give them special opportunities, and to produce the high tech leaders of tomorrow. And our program's small size allows us</p>
<ol>
<li>to offer stimulating and challenging honors courses that even small private schools cannot offer,</li>
<li>to provide significant faculty contact and guidance, and</li>
<li>to foster a supportive community in which students learn from each other and inspire each other.</li>
</ol>
<p>In short, our program is designed to encourage students to do truly amazing things, both during their college career and beyond.</p>
<h2>Benefits</h2>
<h3>Community</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://resilient-sing-a1b.notion.site/image/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fsecure.notion-static.com%2F86ac4f34-20d3-4880-909c-d0c3bc5f9f6d%2FDSC_0103.jpg?table=block&amp;id=9e7c8a16-2e43-4ce1-b94a-ed6abafb8e6e&amp;spaceId=0abb7c3e-d22c-4aec-9dbc-25db245630b8&amp;width=2000&amp;userId=&amp;cache=v2" data-is-external-image="true" ></p>
<p>One of the most important aspects of our program is our community. Turing Scholars bond and make lifelong friends by taking small challenging honors courses as a cohort. This bonding is facilitated by small honors class sizes—typically 30-60—at a time when CS class sizes around the country are booming, even at small private schools. Students also have many opportunities to get to know faculty, and students can form particularly strong relationships with faculty through undergraduate research. This close-knit community extends beyond the classroom, as the Turing Scholars Student Association organizes regular events, such as brunches with professors, potlucks, and excursions into the city.</p>
<h3>Austin</h3>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://resilient-sing-a1b.notion.site/image/https%3A%2F%2Fs3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fsecure.notion-static.com%2Fe390e998-b4fe-4403-9406-621400196d53%2Fryan-duffy-jBghupTmaNQ-unsplash.jpg?table=block&amp;id=ee338304-bb07-42cb-a9c5-ae5b8316f4b7&amp;spaceId=0abb7c3e-d22c-4aec-9dbc-25db245630b8&amp;width=2000&amp;userId=&amp;cache=v2" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Photo via Unsplash" width="673" height="378"></figure>
<p>Austin is a vibrant city that has been the fastest-growing major metropolitan area in the US for nine straight years. With its young, well-educated population, its booming tech industry, and its bustling music and cultural scene, Austin serves as a great backdrop for a college experience.</p>
<h3>Honors Housing</h3>
<p>In their first year at UT, most Turing Scholars choose to live in UT's Honors Living Community, comprised of the four halls in the Honors Quad (Andrews, Blanton, Carothers, and Littlefield) and populated by students from UT's various honors programs. Thus, the Honors Dorms allow Turing Scholars to form ties with some of the university's most talented students.</p>
<h3><span class="notion-enable-hover" data-token-index="0" data-reactroot="">Undergraduate Research Opportunities</span></h3>
<p>An important component of the Turing Scholars degree is an undergraduate honors thesis, which is structured like a miniature PhD thesis, with a faculty advisor who helps shape and guide the research and a committee of faculty members that approves the thesis based on the student's written thesis and oral presentation. While not always publishable, the thesis is intended to be a significant piece of work that is typically conducted over two or more semesters. The honors thesis is often a student's most meaningful component of their college career, and beyond the technical depth required, the experience helps students develop a host of important life skills, including critical thinking, written and oral communication, and organizational and executive skills.</p>
<h3><span class="notion-enable-hover" data-token-index="0" data-reactroot="">Career Opportunities</span></h3>
<p>Turing Scholars are highly sought after by industry. For example, freshman internships in the tech industry are rare, but with our aggressive first-year CS curriculum and our program's stellar reputation, about 75% of our freshmen find summer internships in the tech industry.</p>
<p>Our most recent poll, conducted in 2019, shows that across our freshmen, sophomores and juniors, salaries for summer internships ranged from $20/hour to $95/hour, with a median salary of $50/hour. The same poll showed that the average compensation upon graduation was $148K (including stock grants but excluding signing bonuses).</p>
<p>Our students who choose to pursue a PhD have enjoyed a tremendous record of placement in the top 10 PhD programs.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
